{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "The Treaty of Yandabo was signed in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1802",
          "B. 1826",
          "C. 1830",
          "D. 1832"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 1826"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one is the first Assamese novel",
        "options": [
          "A. Mirijiyori",
          "B. Podum Kunwari",
          "C. Bhanumati",
          "D. Sudharmar Upakhyan"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Bhanumati"
      },
      {
        "question": "The state anthem 'O Mur Apunar Desh' was first published in the magazine named",
        "options": [
          "A. Bahi",
          "B. Jonaki",
          "C. Surabhi",
          "D. Jonbiri"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Bahi"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first Assamese magazine Orunodoi was published in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1836",
          "B. 1846",
          "C. 1872",
          "D. 1882"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 1846"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first Assamese to compile a dictionary named 'HemKosh' is",
        "options": [
          "A. Dimbeswar Neog",
          "B. Chandradhar Barua",
          "C. Hemchandra Goswami",
          "D. Hemchandra Barua"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Hemchandra Barua"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who is the first Assamese to receive 'Jnanpith Award'",
        "options": [
          "A. Indira Goswami",
          "B. Birendra Kumar Bhattacharya",
          "C. Bhupen Hazarika",
          "D. Hemchandra Barua"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Birendra Kumar Bhattacharya"
      },
      {
        "question": "Total number of Districts in Assam",
        "options": [
          "A. 25",
          "B. 26",
          "C. 27",
          "D. 35"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 35"
      },
      {
        "question": "Hiuen Tsang visited Assam during the reign of",
        "options": [
          "A. Pushya Varman",
          "B. Mahendra Varman",
          "C. Bhaskar Varman",
          "D. Brahma Pala"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Bhaskar Varman"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which year, Sukapha established Ahom Kingdom in Charaideo",
        "options": [
          "A. 1253",
          "B. 1272",
          "C. 1296",
          "D. 1309"
        ],
        "answer": "A. 1253"
      },
      {
        "question": "The war of Saraighat was fought between Ahom and Mughal in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1652",
          "B. 1667",
          "C. 1670",
          "D. 1671"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 1671"
      },
      {
        "question": "Mahatma Gandhi first visited Assam in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1918",
          "B. 1919",
          "C. 1920",
          "D. 1921"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 1921"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first book to win Sahitya Akademi Award is",
        "options": [
          "A. Iyaruingam",
          "B. Bonphool",
          "C. Alakananda",
          "D. Pita Putra"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Bonphool"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who is the first barrister of Assam",
        "options": [
          "A. Haliram Deka",
          "B. Pranab Kumar Borooah",
          "C. Anundoram Borooah",
          "D. Parul Das"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Anundoram Borooah"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one is the largest district in Assam by area-wise",
        "options": [
          "A. Barpeta",
          "B. Karbi Anglong",
          "C. Sivsagar",
          "D. Dibrugarh"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Karbi Anglong"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which district, Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary is located",
        "options": [
          "A. Golaghat",
          "B. Sivsagar",
          "C. Karbi Anglong",
          "D. Dibrugarh"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Karbi Anglong"
      }
    ]
  }
  